AMIT SUTHAR

React Developer

(+91)7014780586

mail.com

@amitsuthar803

in/AMITSUTHAR

Portfolio

SUMMARY

React Developer with 2+ years of experience in front-end development. Skilled in React, Tailwind CSS, and Node.js. Experienced in building responsive web apps and optimizing performance with SSR frameworks like Next.js. Also knowledgeable in graphic design and UI/UX to create engaging user interfaces.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)

PSP PG COLLEGE PARTAPUR, RAJASTHAN

2019 - 2022

SCORE: 76.43%

Senior Secondary (12th)

GOVT. SR. SEC. SCHOOL GARHI, RAJASTHAN

2017 - 2018 SCORE: 72.20%

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Internship (MERN stack)

CODSOFT

June 2024 - July 2024

West Bengal, Remote

- Developed full-stack applications using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, and Node.js),
 Gaining Hands-on experience in Building and integrating RESTful APIs, managing databases, and
 Creating dynamic User interfaces.
- Integrated JWT-based authentication middleware to protect sensitive routes and authenticate User's Requests.

Frontend Developer

3CLICKS BRANDING

Mar 2023 – June 2024

Ahmedabad, Gujarat

- Developed and maintained web applications using React, Redux, Context API, hooks, and Tailwind, Along with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap. Focused on enhancing performance, state Management, and component reusability to ensure a seamless User experience across various devices.
- · Worked on 10+ web development projects for company services and figma to html conversion.

Office and Graphic Design Operator

PSP INSTITUTION

Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

Panswara, Rajasthan

• Coordinate office tasks such as scheduling and document management, data entry and while also designing engaging visuals, including YouTube thumbnails, for college events and promotions.

PROJECTS

Spy World | PLive

React, Tailwind, Context API, Firebase

- Developed a mobile-responsive e-commerce site for drones. Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, React, Context API.
- Features: Product catalog, search functionality, user authentication, shopping cart, checkout process, Responsive Design, API integration, Cross-browser compatibility.

Haven Home | <mark>ℰ Live</mark>

React, Tailwind, Context API, Supabase, React Query

- Developed a user-friendly web application for hotel management using React, React Query, Context API, Supabase, and Tailwind CSS.
- Implemented cabin management functionalities including add, update, and delete features.

Memorizer | & Live

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

 Developed a note-taking web application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Implemented user-Friendly Interface, Glass morphism effects, designed for productivity and ease of use.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,
Typescript, React, jQuery,
Bootstrap, Redux, Node.js,
Express.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS

Sass, Styled Components, JSON.

OTHER: C, C++, MVC Architecture, RESTful API, Git, Jest, Next.js, SSR,

Toolkit, AWS.

DESIGN TOOL: Adobe Photoshop,

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD

Figma.

CERTIFICATIONS

POSTMAN - Student Expert

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English